Guide to the Erich Maria Remarque Papers MSS.095
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series 6A: Personal Documents, 1925-1969; 3.25 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box, 2 half manuscript boxes, 1 card box, and 1 oversized flat box.
  This series contains personal and govermental documents issued to Remarque and his family. It includes marriage certificates, travel documents (including passports), certificates, ticket stubs, tax documents, driver's licenses, citizenship documents, leases, documents related to the villa in Porto Ronco, and other documents. Other materials in the series reflect Remarque and his family's persecution by the Nazis--his sister, Elfriede Scholtz was put to death by the Nazis in 1943.
  - Marriage application of Erich Remark, Berlin-Charlottenberg, 1925 (Box 92, Folder 1, Item 1)
  - Copy-editor certification for Remarque, Sport im Bild Schriftleitung, 1927 (Box 92, Folder 1, Item 2)
  - Copy of marriage certificate for Joannes Adamus Remacle und Anna Elisabetha Frenken, Catholic Priest's Office in Düsseldorf-Kaiserswerth, 1937 (Box 92, Folder 1, Item 3)
  - Marriage certificate of Franz Remark und Anna Maria Stallknecht, Catholic Priest's Office St. Marien, 1937 (Box 92, Folder 1, Item 4)
  - Marriage certificate of Gottfried Stallknecht und Elisabeth Pöppinghaus, St. Getrudis Parish, Essen, 1937 (Box 92, Folder 1, Item 5)
  - Settlement Permit, Brissago, 1939 (Box 92, Folder 1, Item 6)
  - Occupational Force Travel Permit, 1955 (Box 92, Folder 1, Item 7)
    Remarque authorized to travel from Vienna, Austria to US Zone Austria and British Zone Austria
  - Certificate of voluntary service, Königliches Katholisches Lehrer-Seminar Osnabrück, 1917 (Box 92, Folder 2, Item 1)
  - Certificate of military award for Remarque, Reserve Hospital Duisburg, 1918 (Box 92, Folder 2, Item 2)
  - Transcript of Elfriede Scholz's death sentence by the People's Court, 1943 (Box 92, Folder 3, Item 1)
  - Petition for clemency for Elfriede Scholz, 1943 (Box 92, Folder 3, Item 2)
  - Penalty order due to currency offense, 1932 (Box 92, Folder 3, Item 3)
  - Speech for the granting of honorary citizenship to the municipalities of Ronco and Ascon, undated (Box 92, Folder 3, Item 4)
  - Speech for the granting of honorary citizenship to the municipalities of Ronco and Ascon, undated (Box 92, Folder 3, Item 5)
  - Articles of Incorporation for Verband Deutscher Schriftsteller, undated (Box 92, Folder 3, Item 6)
  - Invitation to the general meeting of the Broad of Directors of the Schutzverband niedersächsischer Schriftsteller e.V. in Hannover, 1969 (Box 92, Folder 3, Item 7)
  - Dr. Willi A. Koch's Invitation to the general meeting and agenda of the Board of Directors of the Schutzverband niedersächsischer Schriftsteller e.V. in Hannover, 1969 (Box 92, Folder 3, Item 8)
  - Membership certificate for Billy (Remarque's dog) for the Tail-Waggers Club in London, undated (Box 92, Folder 3, Item 9)
  - Free admission to the Degas exhibit at the Ministère de l'éducation nationale (Box 92, Folder 3, Item 10)
  - Monthly pass to the Corviglia Ski Club in St. Moritz, 1956 (Box 92, Folder 3, Item 11)
  - Membership card for the Author's Guild in New York, 1959 (Box 92, Folder 3, Item 12)
  - Postponement of the Lancia auction for one month, 1934-1938 (Box 92, Folder 3, Item 13)
    Includes order of forfeiture by the Secret Police
  - Confiscation of Lancia by the Secret Police and disclosure of availibility, 1936 (Box 92, Folder 3, Item 14)
  - Explanation of repatriation practice, 1956 (Box 92, Folder 3, Item 15)
  - Penalty order due to currency offense, 1932 (Box 92, Folder 3, Item 16)
  - Seizure of Lancia by the Secret Police, 1934 (Box 92, Folder 3, Item 17)
  - Income tax assessment and accompany letter, 1931-1934 (Box 92, Folder 3, Item 18)
  - Letter to lift the seizure of Lancia by the Secret Police, 1935 (Box 92, Folder 3, Item 19)
  - International Certificates of Vaccination, Personal Health History. U.S.Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, undated (Box 92, Folder 4, Item 1)
  - Ilse Remark née Zambona Passport, 1926 (Box 92, Folder 4, Item 2)
  - Ilse Zambona Passport, 1931 (Box 92, Folder 4, Item 3)
  - Entry ticket for eight days at Casino Municipal de Cannes, 1931 (Box 92, Folder 4, Item 4)
  - Passport photography, 1948 (Box 92, Folder 4, Item 5)
  - Swiss Learner's Permit, 1948 (Box 92, Folder 4, Item 6)
  - Passport, 1948 (Box 92, Folder 4, Item 7)
  - Passport, 1952 (Box 92, Folder 4, Item 8)
  - Swiss Driver's license, 1952 (Box 92, Folder 4, Item 9)
  - Passport, 1956 (Box 92, Folder 4, Item 10)
  - Passport, 1960 (Box 92, Folder 4, Item 11)
  - Passport, 1965 (Box 92, Folder 4, Item 12)
  - Identity Certificate, 1939 (Box 92, Folder 4, Item 13)
  - Passport, 1939 (Box 92, Folder 4, Item 14)
  - Will, 1965 (Box 92, Folder 5, Item 1)
  - Stay reconstruction, 1965-1969 (Box 92, Folder 6, Item 1)
  - Stay reconstruction, 1965-1969 (Box 92, Folder 6, Item 2)
  - Stay reconstruction, 1965-1969 (Box 92, Folder 6, Item 3)
  - Unknown addressee, 1969 (Box 92, Folder 6, Item 4)
  - Testament, undated (Box 92, Folder 6, Item 5)
  - Income tax return, 1946 (Box 92, Folder 6, Item 6)
  - Notice of United States naturalization, 1948 (Box 92, Folder 6, Item 7)
  - Rental agreement at 320 East 57th Street, 1951 (Box 92, Folder 6, Item 8)
  - Rental agreement at 320 East 57th Street, 1958 (Box 92, Folder 6, Item 9)
  - Landlord's Report of Lease, 1958 (Box 92, Folder 6, Item 10)
  - Map of the Comune di Ronco with marking of Remarque's property, 1959 (Box 92, Folder 6, Item 11)
  - Map of the Comune di Ronco, 1966 (Box 92, Folder 6, Item 12)
  - Divorce certificate, 1958 (Box 92, Folder 6, Item 13)
  - Confirmation of the direct debit order from Der Weg zurück / The Road Back in favor of the Prussian state, 1935 (Box 92, Folder 7, Item 1)
  - Certificate of honorary citizenship of the municipality of Porto Ronco, 1968 (Box 131, Folder 8, Item 1)
  - Certificate of the Grand Cross of Merit from the Federal Republic of Germany, 1967 (Box 148, Folder 9, Item 1)
  - Cross of Merit in jewel box, 1967 (Box 142, Folder 9, Item 2)
  - Justus-Möser-Medaille, 1964 (Box 142)
  - Certificate for the Justus-Möser-Medaille from the city of Osnabrück, 1964 (Box 148, Folder 10, Item 1)
  - Cantone Ticino -- residence permit, 1935 (Box 114, Folder 11, Item 1)
- Series 6C: Astrology Documents and Correspondence, 1941-1968; 0.5 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box.
  This series contains correspondence from astrologers, birth charts, and other materials related to horoscopes and astrology.
  - Astrological calendar, undated (Box 93, Folder 1, Item 1)
  - Horoscope, undated (Box 93, Folder 1, Item 2)
  - G. v. Kaenel, 1954 (Box 93, Folder 1, Item 3-4)
  - Horoscope, undated (Box 93, Folder 1, Item 5)
  - NW, undated (Box 93, Folder 1, Item 6)
  - Inest Brown, 1941 (Box 93, Folder 2, Item 1)
  - Hugh MacCraig, 1948 (Box 93, Folder 2, Item 2)
  - Mrs. Johnson, 1952-1953 (Box 93, Folder 2, Item 3)
  - Carroll Righter, 1952-1968 (Box 93, Folder 3, Item 1-20)
  - Horoscope, 1940 (Box 93, Folder 3, Item 21)
  - "Silver Lining!", 1952 (Box 93, Folder 3, Item 22)
  - "800 New Galaxies Discovered. By Mt. Palomar Observatory, Washington, 17.06.", undated (Box 93, Folder 3, Item 23)
- Series 6D: Financial and Business Correspondence, 1927-1970; 1.5 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes and 2 half manuscript boxes.
  This series contains financial documents and correspondence with banks, companies, utilities, and other services regarding purchases and investments, often related to the art market.
  - Statutory declaration, after 1935 (Box 93, Folder 1, Item 1-2)
  - Attilio Zamolini, 1932 (Box 93, Folder 1, Item 3)
  - Max Lion, Hans Reich, 1934 (Box 93, Folder 1, Item 4)
  - Writ of execution, 1936 (Box 93, Folder 1, Item 5)
  - Report on G.G. Chamberlain, director of 'Sumpoil Ltd.', 1936 (Box 93, Folder 1, Item 6)
  - Hanns Frankenberg, 1937 (Box 93, Folder 1, Item 7)
  - Hardy & Co., 1939 (Box 93, Folder 1, Item 8)
  - Foreigner affidavit, after 1937 (Box 93, Folder 1, Item 9)
  - Attilio Zamolini, 1940 (Box 93, Folder 1, Item 10)
  - Attilio Zamolini To W. Feilchenfeldt, 1941 (Box 93, Folder 1, Item 11)
  - Attilio Zamolini, 1942-1947 (Box 93, Folder 1, Item 12-15)
  - Share certificate in Lexington Productions, Inc., 1946 (Box 93, Folder 1, Item 16)
  - Hardy & Co., 1950 (Box 93, Folder 1, Item 17)
  - Julius Bär & Co., 1960 (Box 93, Folder 1, Item 18)
  - Robert M. W. Kempner, R. I. Levin, 1961 (Box 93, Folder 1, Item 19)
  - Morgan Guaranty Trust Co., 1967 (Box 93, Folder 1, Item 20)
  - Sales tax return, 1967 (Box 93, Folder 1, Item 21)
  - Shareholder Voting Form -- Sperry Rand Corporation, 1967 (Box 93, Folder 1, Item 22)
  - US & Foreign Securities Corporation, undated (Box 93, Folder 1, Item 23)
  - Sergio Salvioni, 1969 (Box 93, Folder 1, Item 24)
  - Wirtschaftsbank für Niederdeutschland -- banking materials, 1932 (Box 93, Folder 2, Item 1-4)
  - Basler Handelsbank Zürich -- checkbook, 1933-1934 (Box 93, Folder 2, Item 5)
  - Postal receipt, 1927 (Box 93, Folder 2, Item 6)
  - Raudis & Cie. -- receipts, 1928 (Box 93, Folder 2, Item 7-8)
  - Dresdner Bank -- check, 1931 (Box 93, Folder 2, Item 9)
  - Lloyds and National, 1936 (Box 93, Folder 2, Item 10)
  - Cancelleria Municipale, 1936 (Box 93, Folder 2, Item 11)
  - Gebr. Arnhold, 1936-1937 (Box 93, Folder 2, Item 12)
  - H. Paetz, Rhodius Koenigs, Handel-Maatschappij, 1939 (Box 93, Folder 2, Item 13)
  - Hardy & Co., 1938-1941 (Box 93, Folder 2, Item 14-19)
  - Morgan Guaranty Trust Co., 1944 (Box 93, Folder 2, Item 20)
  - Schweizerische Kreditanstalt, 1954 (Box 93, Folder 3, Item 1)
  - Banca della Svizzera Italiana, 1958 (Box 93, Folder 3, Item 2-3)
  - List of taxed income, 1959 (Box 93, Folder 3, Item 4)
  - Sperry Rand Corporation, 1963 (Box 93, Folder 3, Item 5)
  - Morgan Guaranty Trust Co. -- checkbook, 1963-1968 (Box 93, Folder 3, Item 6)
  - Unione di Banche Svizzere, 1965 (Box 93, Folder 3, Item 7-8)
  - Meredith Press, 1965 (Box 93, Folder 3, Item 9)
  - List of taxed income, 1966 (Box 93, Folder 3, Item 10)
  - Zürcher Kantonalbank, undated (Box 93, Folder 3, Item 11)
  - Unione di Banche Svizzere, 1966 (Box 93, Folder 3, Item 12-13)
  - Zürcher Kantonalbank, 1966 (Box 93, Folder 3, Item 14)
  - Unione di Banche Svizzere, 1966 (Box 93, Folder 3, Item 15-16)
  - Süddeutscher Rundfunk, 1967 (Box 93, Folder 3, Item 17)
  - Day & Meyer, Murray & Young Corp., 1967 (Box 93, Folder 3, Item 18)
  - Morgan Guaranty Trust Co., 1967 (Box 93, Folder 3, Item 19-20)
  - Stadtsparkasse, 1967 (Box 93, Folder 3, Item 21)
  - Morgan Guaranty Trust Co., 1967 (Box 93, Folder 3, Item 22)
  - Banca della Svizzera Italiana, 1967 (Box 93, Folder 4, Item 1)
  - Morgan Guaranty Trust Co., 1967 (Box 93, Folder 4, Item 2-4)
  - Day & Meyer, Murray & Young Corp., undated (Box 93, Folder 4, Item 5)
  - Morgan Guaranty Trust Co., 1967 (Box 93, Folder 4, Item 6)
  - Schweizerische Kreditanstalt, 1967 (Box 93, Folder 4, Item 7)
  - Schweizerische Bankgesellschaft, undated (Box 93, Folder 4, Item 8)
  - Morgan Guaranty Trust Co., 1967 (Box 93, Folder 4, Item 9)
  - Copyright Agency Sophie Lussarar, 1967 (Box 93, Folder 4, Item 10)
  - Unione di Banche Svizzere, 1967 (Box 93, Folder 4, Item 11)
  - Julius Bär & Co., 1967 (Box 93, Folder 4, Item 12-13)
  - Banca della Svizzera Italiana, 1967 (Box 93, Folder 4, Item 14)
  - Schweizerische Kreditanstalt, 1967 (Box 93, Folder 4, Item 15)
  - Julius Bär & Co., 1967 (Box 93, Folder 4, Item 16)
  - Morgan Guaranty Trust Co., 1967 (Box 93, Folder 4, Item 17)
  - Julius Bär & Co., 1967 (Box 93, Folder 4, Item 18)
  - Morgan Guaranty Trust Co., 1968 (Box 93, Folder 4, Item 19)
  - Unione di Banche Svizzere, 1968 (Box 93, Folder 5, Item 1)
  - Schweizerische Bankgesellschaft, 1968 (Box 93, Folder 5, Item 2)
  - Julius Bär & Co., 1968 (Box 93, Folder 5, Item 3)
  - Atheneum Publishers, 1968 (Box 93, Folder 5, Item 4)
  - Lehman Corporation, 1968 (Box 93, Folder 5, Item 5)
  - Deutsche Bank, 1968 (Box 93, Folder 5, Item 6)
  - Morgan Guaranty Trust Co., 1968 (Box 93, Folder 5, Item 7)
  - Deutsche Bank, 1968 (Box 93, Folder 5, Item 8)
  - Morgan Guaranty Trust Co., 1968 (Box 93, Folder 5, Item 9)
  - Unione di Banche Svizzere, 1968 (Box 93, Folder 5, Item 10)
  - Banca della Svizzera Italiana, 1968 (Box 93, Folder 5, Item 11)
  - Unione di Banche Svizzere, 1968 (Box 93, Folder 5, Item 12)
  - Julius Bär & Co., 1968 (Box 93, Folder 5, Item 13)
  - Schweizerische Kreditanstalt, 1968 (Box 93, Folder 5, Item 14)
  - Banca Popolare Svizzera, 1968 (Box 93, Folder 5, Item 15)
  - Zürcher Kantonalbank, 1968 (Box 93, Folder 5, Item 16)
  - Union de Banques Suisses, 1968 (Box 93, Folder 5, Item 17)
  - Schweizerische Kreditanstalt, 1968 (Box 93, Folder 5, Item 18)
  - Unione di Banche Svizzere, 1968 (Box 93, Folder 5, Item 19)
  - Henri Bendel, 1969 (Box 93, Folder 5, Item 20)
  - Maerki, Baumann & Co., 1937-1948 (Box 93, Folder 6, Item 1-11)
  - Morgan Guaranty Trust Co., 1951 (Box 93, Folder 6, Item 12-13)
  - Lloyds & National Provincial Foreign Bank Ltd., 1938-1949 (Box 93, Folder 6, Item 14-18)
  - Morgan Guaranty Trust Co., 1949 (Box 93, Folder 6, Item 19)
  - Unknown sender, 1939 (Box 93, Folder 6, Item 20)
  - Notes, 1946-1963 (Box 93, Folder 7, Item 1-8)
  - L. Radopna, 1968 (Box 93, Folder 7, Item 9)
  - Notes, 1957-1968 (Box 93, Folder 7, Item 9a-17)
  - Unknown sender, undated (Box 93, Folder 7, Item 18)
  - Paulette Goddard, undated (Box 93, Folder 7, Item 19)
  - Receipts, 1952 (Box 93, Folder 7, Item 20-22)
  - Joel E. Sammet, 1944 (Box 94, Folder 8, Item 1)
  - Affidavit translation, Berlin Internal Revenue Department, 1932 (Box 94, Folder 8, Item 2)
  - Notes, 1932-1939 (Box 94, Folder 8, Item 3-7)
  - Fides Treuhand-Vereinigung, undated (Box 94, Folder 9, Item 1-4)
  - Ernst Kiefer, undated (Box 94, Folder 9, Item 5)
  - Julius Hirsig, undated (Box 94, Folder 9, Item 6)
  - "Erläuterungen über Anstalten nach Liechtensteinischem Recht", undated (Box 94, Folder 9, Item 7)
  - Fides Treuhand-Vereinigung, 1953-1960 (Box 94, Folder 9, Item 8-12)
  - "Erläuterungen über Anstalten nach Liechtensteinischem Recht", undated (Box 94, Folder 9, Item 13)
  - Morgan Guaranty Trust Co. -- checkbook, 1967-1969 (Box 94, Folder 10, Item 1-2)
  - Schweizerische Kreditanstalt -- checkbook, 1963-1970 (Box 94, Folder 10, Item 3)
  - Nelson Doubleday, Inc. -- check, 1959 (Box 94, Folder 10, Item 4)
  - Morgan Guaranty Trust Co. -- checks, 1961-1966 (Box 94, Folder 10, Item 5)
  - Schweizerische Kreditanstalt -- checkbook, 1970 (Box 94, Folder 10, Item 6)
  - Dipartimento Cantonale di Polizia, 1939 (Box 94, Folder 10, Item 7)
  - Ongaro Salvioni, 1965 (Box 94, Folder 10, Item 8)
  - Attilio Decamilli, undated (Box 94, Folder 11, Item 1)
  - Receipt for plants, undated (Box 94, Folder 11, Item 2-3)
  - Photo album -- Pancaldi, Ascona, undated (Box 94, Folder 11, Item 4-5)
  - Scholze u. Pötzschke, 1926 (Box 94, Folder 11, Item 6)
  - Ruth Albu -- household accounting, 1932 (Box 94, Folder 11, Item 7)
  - Arrangement of household items, undated (Box 94, Folder 11, Item 8)
  - Otakar Hurka, undated (Box 94, Folder 11, Item 9)
  - Erich Rosam, 1932 (Box 94, Folder 11, Item 10)
  - Theophil Spörri, 1932 (Box 94, Folder 11, Item 11)
  - Paul Rausch to Ruth Albu, 1932 (Box 94, Folder 11, Item 12)
  - Möhrke & Hartmann in Berlin to Ruth Albu, 1932 (Box 94, Folder 11, Item 13)
  - G. Kiefer, 1932 (Box 94, Folder 11, Item 14)
  - Lido-Kursae, 1934 (Box 94, Folder 11, Item 15)
  - Courvoisier Ltd., 1933 (Box 94, Folder 11, Item 16)
  - Theophil Spörri, 1933 (Box 94, Folder 11, Item 17-18)
  - Singer, 1933 (Box 94, Folder 11, Item 19)
  - A. Koelliker & Co. AG to Ilse Jutta Zambona, 1934 (Box 94, Folder 11, Item 20)
  - Frederico Barra, 1934 (Box 94, Folder 11, Item 21)
  - Mario Danzi, 1934 (Box 94, Folder 11, Item 22)
  - H. Sichel & Sons, Ltd., 1934 (Box 94, Folder 11, Item 23)
  - Municipalità Ronco, 1934 (Box 94, Folder 11, Item 24)
  - Kurhaus Collinetta, 1935 (Box 94, Folder 11, Item 25)
  - Theophil Spörri, 1937-1938 (Box 94, Folder 12, Item 1-4)
  - Ignace Opelka & Comp., 1938 (Box 94, Folder 12, Item 5)
  - Theophil Spörri, 1938 (Box 94, Folder 12, Item 6)
  - Naretto's Coloniali, 1940 (Box 94, Folder 12, Item 7)
  - Patek, Philippe & Co., 1950 (Box 94, Folder 12, Item 8)
  - Guido Maestrini Galleria della Moda, 1951 (Box 94, Folder 12, Item 9)
  - Otto Caracciola & Co, 1952 (Box 94, Folder 12, Item 10)
  - Unknown sender, 1952 (Box 94, Folder 12, Item 11)
  - Lucien Magnant, 1954 (Box 94, Folder 12, Item 12)
  - Oskar Schultz, Zwerg- und Kaninchenteckelzwinger, 1955 (Box 94, Folder 12, Item 13)
  - Goth & Co., 1956 (Box 94, Folder 12, Item 14)
  - Day & Meyer, Murray & Young, 1957 (Box 94, Folder 12, Item 15-16)
  - Mon Sachet, 1956 (Box 94, Folder 12, Item 17)
  - Day & Meyer, Murray & Young, 1959 (Box 94, Folder 12, Item 18)
  - New York Telephone Company, 1960 (Box 94, Folder 12, Item 19-20)
  - Masini/Masini e Cipriani, 1963 (Box 94, Folder 12, Item 21)
  - Ufficio Cantonale della Circolazione, 1963 (Box 94, Folder 12, Item 23)
  - Ernesto Camponovo, 1963 (Box 94, Folder 12, Item 24)
  - Grieder & Cie AG, 1963 (Box 94, Folder 12, Item 25)
  - Konditorei Rabien, 1965 (Box 94, Folder 12, Item 26)
  - Van Cleef & Arpels, 1964 (Box 94, Folder 12, Item 27)
  - Manfred Greiling, 1965 (Box 94, Folder 13, Item 1)
  - Wittmann, 1965 (Box 94, Folder 13, Item 2)
  - Automobile Club Svizzero, 1965 (Box 94, Folder 13, Item 3)
  - PTT, 1965 (Box 94, Folder 13, Item 4-7)
  - Wintherthur Unfall, 1967 (Box 94, Folder 13, Item 8)
  - PTT, 1967 (Box 94, Folder 13, Item 9-12)
  - Gübelin, Emil Krebs, 1967 (Box 94, Folder 13, Item 13)
  - Pancaldi, 1965 (Box 94, Folder 13, Item 14)
  - Bucherer, 1965 (Box 94, Folder 13, Item 15)
  - Aldo Natali, 1966 (Box 94, Folder 13, Item 16)
  - Rudolf Schmidlin & Co., 1966 (Box 94, Folder 13, Item 17)
  - Gianfranco Pinoja, 1966 (Box 94, Folder 13, Item 18-19)
  - Giovanni Schober, 1966 (Box 94, Folder 13, Item 20)
  - Florist, Inc., 1966 (Box 94, Folder 13, Item 21)
  - Fritz von Falkenhayn, 1967 (Box 94, Folder 13, Item 22)
  - Giovanni Schober, 1966-1967 (Box 94, Folder 13, Item 23)
  - G. Bianchi AG, 1967 (Box 94, Folder 13, Item 24)
  - Claim Agency, 1967 (Box 94, Folder 14, Item 1)
  - Giovanni Schober, undated (Box 94, Folder 14, Item 2)
  - Società Elettrica Sopracenerina, 1966 (Box 94, Folder 14, Item 3)
  - Gübelin, 1967 (Box 94, Folder 14, Item 4)
  - Rudolf Schmidlin & Co., 1967 (Box 94, Folder 14, Item 5)
  - G. Bianchi AG, 1967 (Box 94, Folder 14, Item 6)
  - Konditorei Rabien, 1967 (Box 94, Folder 14, Item 7)
  - Florist, Inc., 1967 (Box 94, Folder 14, Item 8)
  - Konditorei Rabien, 1967 (Box 94, Folder 14, Item 9)
  - Blumen Marsano, 1967 (Box 94, Folder 14, Item 10)
  - Florist, Inc., 1968 (Box 94, Folder 14, Item 11)
  - Weinkellerei St. Gotthard Caspar E. Manz, 1968 (Box 94, Folder 14, Item 12)
  - Response to telegram from Darmstadt TF, 1968 (Box 94, Folder 14, Item 13)
  - Konditorei Rabien, 1968 (Box 94, Folder 14, Item 14)
  - Helvetia Feuer, Dr. Ermes Borsani, 1969 (Box 94, Folder 14, Item 15)
  - G. Nardi, 1969 (Box 94, Folder 14, Item 16)
  - Remarque, 1956 (Box 94, Folder 14, Item 17)
  - Baur au Lac, undated (Box 94, Folder 15, Item 1)
  - Remarque, undated (Box 94, Folder 15, Item 2)
  - La Maison Rouge, undated (Box 94, Folder 15, Item 3-4)
  - Air France, undated (Box 94, Folder 15, Item 5)
  - Unknown sender, undated (Box 94, Folder 15, Item 6)
  - Hotel Ritz, undated (Box 94, Folder 15, Item 7)
  - Unknown sender, 1925 (Box 94, Folder 15, Item 8)
  - Hotel du Cap d'Antibes, circa 1931 (Box 94, Folder 15, Item 9)
  - Grand Prix Automobile de Monaco ticket, 1931 (Box 94, Folder 15, Item 10)
  - Palace Hotel in St. Moritz, 1936 (Box 94, Folder 15, Item 11)
  - Swissair, 1951 (Box 94, Folder 15, Item 12)
  - Trans World Airline, before 1957 (Box 94, Folder 15, Item 13)
  - Air France, 1956 (Box 94, Folder 15, Item 14)
  - Trans World Airline, 1957 (Box 94, Folder 15, Item 15)
  - KLM, 1954 (Box 94, Folder 15, Item 16)
  - Hotel Steinplatz, 1957 (Box 94, Folder 15, Item 17-21)
  - Capital Airlines, 1957 (Box 94, Folder 15, Item 22-23)
  - Swissair, 1957 (Box 94, Folder 15, Item 24)
  - Pan American World Airways System, 1957 (Box 94, Folder 15, Item 25)
  - Swissair, 1957 (Box 94, Folder 15, Item 26)
  - Trans World Airline, 1957 (Box 94, Folder 15, Item 27)
  - Restaurant Hotel Ritz, 1956 (Box 94, Folder 15, Item 28)
  - Società Haliana Radio Marittima, 1966 (Box 94, Folder 15, Item 29)
  - Arcade Bücherei, 1966 (Box 94, Folder 15, Item 30)
  - Hotel Danieli Royal Excelsior, 1969 (Box 94, Folder 15, Item 31)
  - Hotel Excelsior Halie, 1967 (Box 94, Folder 15, Item 32)
  - Flora Hotel, 1969 (Box 94, Folder 15, Item 33)
  - Hotel Excelsior, 1969 (Box 94, Folder 15, Item 34)
  - Grand Hotel de la Ville, 1967 (Box 94, Folder 15, Item 35)
  - Hotel Ritz, 1956 (Box 94, Folder 15, Item 36)
  - Max Fröhlich, 1932 (Box 94, Folder 16, Item 1)
  - Quadri, Giacometti & Reglin, 1937 (Box 94, Folder 16, Item 2)
  - M. Herrmann-Scheuter Orientteppiche, undated (Box 94, Folder 16, Item 3)
  - Aldo Natali, 1955-1956 (Box 94, Folder 16, Item 4-17)
  - Armando Neermann, 1958 (Box 94, Folder 16, Item 18)
  - Francesco Genova, 1958 (Box 94, Folder 16, Item 19)
  - Stuttgarter Kunstkabinett R. N. Ketterer, undated (Box 94, Folder 17, Item 1)
  - Galerie Maurice Chalom, 1961 (Box 94, Folder 17, Item 2)
  - Galleria d'Antichità, 1966 (Box 94, Folder 17, Item 3)
  - Gertrude Fehr, 1966 (Box 94, Folder 17, Item 4)
  - Marlborough-Gerson Gallery, 1966 (Box 94, Folder 17, Item 5)
  - Yamanaka & Co., undated (Box 94, Folder 17, Item 6)
  - City Art Museum of St. Louis, 1966 (Box 94, Folder 17, Item 7)
  - Sotheby & Co., 1966 (Box 94, Folder 17, Item 8)
  - Vulcan Freight Services, 1967 (Box 94, Folder 17, Item 9)
  - International Art Market, 1967 (Box 94, Folder 17, Item 10)
  - Eredi R. Starnini, 1968 (Box 94, Folder 17, Item 11)
  - Day & Meyer, Murray & Young, 1969 (Box 94, Folder 17, Item 12-13)
  - Liberia della Rondine, 1954 (Box 94, Folder 18, Item 1)
  - Buchhandlung Karl Buchholz, undated (Box 94, Folder 18, Item 2)
  - Argus Nachrichtenbüro, 1954 (Box 94, Folder 18, Item 3)
  - Libris, 1954 (Box 94, Folder 18, Item 4)
  - Scherz season ticket, undated (Box 94, Folder 19, Item 1)
  - Filmfestival Locarnu program, 1955 (Box 94, Folder 19, Item 2)
  - "Le grand prix, Clairefrance", undated (Box 94, Folder 19, Item 3)
  - Receipt, undated (Box 94, Folder 19, Item 4)
  - Program for the 1898 anniversary trip, 1963 (Box 94, Folder 19, Item 5)
  - Robert Abegg, 1931 (Box 114, Folder 20, Item 1)
    Plan for "Casa Monte Tabor" extension
  - "Casa Monte Tabor" extension, 1935 (Box 114, Folder 20, Item 2)
  - Dipartimento delle Publiche Construzioni to Robert Abegg, 1934 (Box 114, Folder 20, Item 3-5)
  - Rampazzi -- cost estimate, 1937 (Box 114, Folder 20, Item 6)
  - Leo Reichensperger -- cost estimate, 1937 (Box 114, Folder 20, Item 7)
  - Commune di Ronco, 1946 (Box 114, Folder 20, Item 8)
  - Società Elettrica Sopracenerina, 1951 (Box 114, Folder 20, Item 9)
  - Jacky, Maeder & Co., 1955 (Box 114, Folder 20, Item 10)
  - Studio Zanolini, 1936 (Box 114, Folder 20, Item 11)
  - Robert Abegg, 1932 (Box 114, Folder 20, Item 12-13)
  - Certificate of mailing, 1935 (Box 114, Folder 20, Item 14)
  - Cassa Cantonale Ticino, 1935 (Box 114, Folder 20, Item 15)
  - Società Svizzera di Assicurazione, 1935 (Box 114, Folder 20, Item 16)
  - Helvetia in St. Gallen, 1935-1939 (Box 114, Folder 20, Item 17-19)
  - Ufficio dei Registri -- purchase certificate for "Casa Monte Tabor", 1931 (Box 114, Folder 21, Item 1)
  - Alpina, 1932 (Box 114, Folder 22, Item 1)
  - F.E. Link to Attilio Zanolini, 1948 (Box 114, Folder 22, Item 2-3)
  - Studio Zanolini, 1948 (Box 114, Folder 22, Item 4-5)